<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="reminders">
        <item>You take care of yourself and present yourself well.  Do something today to put your best (dressed?) foot forward—pay special attention to something you like about the way you look, dress, or groom yourself. </item>
        <item>You are healthy and wellness is important to you.  Do something extra to take care of yourself—eat some fruit or veggies, take a nap, take a cleansing breath, and appreciate your healthy body and all it is doing for you.</item>
        <item>You are agile and physically competent.  It may feel strange and awkward as your baby grows and your body changes, but you can adjust to this and keep your balance.  Try something out:  maybe some yoga, or a gentle stretching, and see how your centre of gravity is changing.  Appreciate your awareness of your body, and the little person doing somersaults within.</item>
        <item>You are fit and strong; this will help both you and your baby over the next few months and years. Do something physical you enjoy today—take a walk, or during your regular exercise, pause to appreciate your body—all the work it is doing to grow your baby, and how your care for yourself contributes to holding your baby in a safe, strong womb.</item>
        <item>You are clever and practical, able to solve the problems that pop up in life.  Think about the last time someone came to you with a problem, and you helped them to solve it.  How did you do that?  Are you intuitive, and the answer just seems to appear to you, or do you work things out logically, stepwise—or a bit of both?  What do you think is your best strategy for solving problems?</item>
        <item>You are imaginative, innovative, inspired.  This may show in creative work, or play, or in the way you go about your daily chores.  Put a bit of extra spark into something you do today—be playful, and surprise yourself!</item>
        <item>You are a good communicator—you express yourself well and get your point across.  Think about something you have to convey to someone today—either in person, or in writing—and stop to think through how you’ve done it, and what works well about that. </item>
        <item>You are good at hands-on projects—making things work, putting things together.  Think about a project you are working on, or planning:  what is the next step?  What is satisfying about doing it?</item>
        <item>You’ve got a good memory—think about how you use this skill to make your day better:  take a minute to  wander in your happiest memory; remember a friend’s birthday or something special you meant to do.</item>
        <item>You are a very focused person; you can use that to tune in to what you need to do, or what helps you, and screen out worries or troubles you don’t need to think about right now.</item>
        <item>You have an amazing fund of facts—interesting things you know about. Consider Merlin’s advice:   “The best thing for being sad," replied Merlin, beginning to puff and blow, \"is to learn something. That's the only thing that never fails\” (T.H. White, The Once and Future King)</item>
        <item>You are a mental explorer, curious and excited to find new things around every corner.  Think now, what have you noticed today that is fascinating, that deserves a second look?  Find out something new about it.</item>
        <item>You are considerate and thoughtful of others.  Do something—a smile, a supportive e-mail, a cup of coffee—for someone else today, and then see if you can do that for yourself, too:  give yourself a treat, a moment to appreciate something you’ve done.</item>
        <item>You are friendly and approachable—say hello to someone new, or take a moment to ask a friend or acquaintance about themselves—and enjoy listening, seeing the spark that is genuine and interesting in that person, today.</item>
        <item>You are a faithful and loyal person, and people know they can count on you to be alongside them in their times of trouble.  In your own difficult times, try to treat yourself as you would a friend:  what do you need?  Who are your loyal friends?  Look to your internal compass and see what is important to you—let that guide you in your steps.</item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
        <item>sample text sample text sample text sample text sample text </item>
    </string-array>

</resources>