<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!-- General -->
    <string name="app_name">BioFeedBack</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>

    <!-- Main -->
    <string name="welcome_welcome">Welcome</string>
    <string name="welcome_text">For the most personalised experience, take some time to answer a few configuration questions in the self assessment </string>
    <string name="welcome_text_part2">.. or just get going with some exercises.</string>
    <string name="welcome_welcome_middle">Welcome back</string>
    <string name="welcome_text_middle">Why don\'t you take some time and answer more configuration questions. It will give a more personalised experience</string>
    <string name="welcome_text_part2_middle">.. you can always go directly to the exercises.</string>
    <string name="welcome_welcome_top">Welcome, NAME</string>
    <string name="welcome_text_top">You can adjust your configuration here </string>
    <string name="welcome_text_part2_top">.. or do some recommended exercises.</string>

    <!-- assessment -->
    <string name="assessment1">Resources and Strengths</string>
    <string name="assessment2">Stress Management</string>
    <string name="assessment3">Strategies</string>
    <string name="assessment4">Destress</string>
    <string name="assessment5">Healthy Choices</string>
    <string name="physical_subheading">Physical</string>
    <string name="intellectual_subheading">Intellectual</string>
    <string name="social_subheading">Social</string>
    <string name="individual_subheading">Individual</string>
    <string name="strategy_subheading">Stress Management</string>
    <string name="physical_question_1"><b>Appearance:</b>  How do you feel about how you look? Is this your strong suit, something you care about and spend energy on looking nice?</string>
    <string name="physical_question_2"><b>Health:</b>  How is your overall health—are you generally sick, or healthy?  Most of the time (irrespective of whether you’ve got a cold right now, or any minor pregnancy woes), do you consider yourself to be in good health?</string>
    <string name="physical_question_3"><b>Motor skills/coordination:</b> Are you the sort of person who can pick up a new sport quickly?  Dance? Feel confident about how you move and do things, physically?</string>
    <string name="physical_question_4"><b>Fitness:</b> Are you generally physically fit, with good stamina?</string>
    <string name="intellectual_question_1"><b>Problem-solving:</b> How are you at figuring out how to get something done—when faced with a problem, thinking of what you need to do to fix it?</string>
    <string name="intellectual_question_2"><b>Creativity:</b> Do you think of new and different ways to do things—put your own twist on it?</string>
    <string name="intellectual_question_3"><b>Verbal skills:</b> How good are you at understanding things you hear and read, and communicating—telling others what you want to tell them, in writing or orally?	</string>
    <string name="intellectual_question_4"><b>Visual-spatial:</b> How good are you at doing things in the non-verbal world—like puzzles, drawing, sewing, mechanical things, using a map?</string>
    <string name="intellectual_question_5"><b>Memory:</b> How is your memory?  Generally, can you remember what you need to do?  What you once learned?  What you need at the store?  That person’s name?</string>
    <string name="intellectual_question_6"><b>Concentration:</b> Can you usually focus on what you need to do, and maintain that focus for a reasonable amount of time—30—60 minutes, depending on the activity?</string>
    <string name="intellectual_question_7"><b>Knowledge:</b> Are you a font of information?  Do you know a lot of things…useful or not?</string>
    <string name="intellectual_question_8"><b>Curiosity:</b> Do you find yourself interested in new things, easily engaged with finding out about some new idea, activity, place to go?</string>
    <string name="social_question_1"><b>Compassion and kindness:</b> Do you think of others frequently, try to take on their perspective, wonder how they are doing? </string>
    <string name="social_question_2"><b>Friendliness:</b> Are you welcoming to others, curious about them, inviting them to talk about themselves, allowing them to get to know you?</string>
    <string name="social_question_3"><b>Loyalty:</b> Are you steadfast and faithful, sticking by people you care about, and true to ideals you hold?</string>
    <string name="social_question_4"><b>Gregariousness:</b> Are you outgoing, comfortable in a crowd of new people, excited to meet and talk with strangers?</string>
    <string name="social_question_5"><b>Honesty:</b> Are you consistently truthful and sincere, not prone to change the story or play with the facts a bit?</string>
    <string name="social_question_6"><b>Courtesy:</b> Are you polite, careful to put others at ease and know the appropriate rules for the occasion?</string>
    <string name="social_question_7"><b>Discretion/tact:</b> Are you thoughtful about what you say and do, keeping secrets when appropriate, considering others and avoiding giving offense? </string>
    <string name="social_question_8"><b>Generosity:</b> Are you open-handed, giving freely of your time and resources?</string>
    <string name="social_question_9"><b>Helpfulness:</b> Do you help others when you see their need?</string>
    <string name="social_question_10"><b>Modesty:</b> Are you low-key about your talents and accomplishments, avoiding boasting or vanity?</string>
    <string name="social_question_11"><b>Sensitivity:</b> Are you attuned to the feelings and reactions of others, as well as your own?</string>
    <string name="social_question_12"><b>Forgiveness:</b> Do you forgive others when they have done something that hurt you, or went against your values?</string>
    <string name="social_question_13"><b>Leadership:</b> Are you the sort of person who can take the lead in a group and inspire people to work together and accomplish their goals?</string>
    <string name="social_question_14"><b>Affection:</b>Are you a person who can express your love and affection easily and openly, telling people you care and showing your love?</string>
    <string name="individual_question_1"><b>Persistence/perseverance:</b> Do you keep on going, pushing through problems, no matter what?</string>
    <string name="individual_question_2"><b>Faith:</b> Do you have faith in the way the world works, whether in formal religion or a personal spiritual understanding?</string>
    <string name="individual_question_3"><b>Sense of humour:</b> Can you see the humour in life, both finding it yourself and appreciating the humour of others? </string>
    <string name="individual_question_4"><b>Patience:</b> Are you able to tolerate delays and bumps in the road without becoming overly upset or frustrated? </string>
    <string name="individual_question_5"><b>Reliability:</b> Do you consistently do what you say you will do—so others can count on you if you say you will do something? </string>
    <string name="individual_question_6"><b>Responsibility:</b> Do you acknowledge what you have done, right or wrong? </string>
    <string name="individual_question_7"><b>Courage:</b> Do you persist in the face of fear, and attempt things others might find too daunting to approach?</string>
    <string name="individual_question_8"><b>Confidence:</b> Do you have faith in yourself, and expect that you will be able to accomplish what you set out to do? </string>
    <string name="individual_question_9"><b>Enthusiasm:</b> Do you plunge into things with energy and joy, and the expectation that whatever it is will be a good thing?</string>
    <string name="individual_question_10"><b>Flexibility:</b> Can you change tactics when what you are doing isn’t working?  Try different things and ways of behaving?  </string>
    <string name="individual_question_11"><b>Hopefulness/optimism:</b> Do you tend to expect things will come out all right in the end?  Do you see the bright side, usually, and see the glass as half full?  </string>
    <string name="individual_question_12"><b>Resourcefulness:</b> Can you find a way to use what you have, to get the job done?</string>
    <string name="individual_question_13"><b>Resiliency/toughness:</b> When things go wrong, do you stand up to it and keep on going?  Are you able to bounce back from hard times? </string>
    <string name="individual_question_14"><b>Stewardship:</b> Do you use what you have wisely, not wasting resources of whatever sort? </string>
    <string name="individual_question_15"><b>Thankfulness:</b> Do you recognise and appreciate what you have, and the good things in the world around you?</string>
    <string name="individual_question_16"><b>Organisation:</b> Are you good at making plans, keeping things in order and keeping track of the events and objects of your life?</string>
    <string name="stress_question_1"><b>Exercise: </b> Moderate exercise can help with anxiety and stress almost immediately, and if you exercise regularly, it can improve mood and energy levels.  Of course, while you are pregnant, you should check with your maternity caregiver, especially if you are starting something new—but even 10 or 15 minutes a day of walking (ideally outside, in the sunlight) can give you a boost.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_2"><b>Mini-break: </b>If you find yourself getting wound up—or just have a few minutes between things—give yourself a mini-break.  Breathe, slowly, and stop:  focus on what is happening now, around you.  Look at a tree, or the sky, or even the lovely symmetry of the steering wheel…just be.  Choose a mantra—some words to say to yourself. </string>
    <string name="stress_question_3"><b>Biofeedback: </b>Practice getting your body to settle down, with some kind of cue (that’s the feedback) about your level of physiological stress (that’s the bio).  With the __ module, it’s showing you your heart rate, so you can see how, when you breathe slowly and settle your thoughts, your body gets settled, too.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_4"><b>Journaling: </b>Many people find that writing about their feelings and thoughts helps to make them clearer, and can sometimes help clear them out of your head.  Get a notebook, and write for 10 minutes—don’t worry about anyone else every seeing it—just write what you really feel. Or do it on a computer or tablet—whatever works for you.  Then close the book/file.  This can help for worries, frustrations, and confusion.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_5"><b>Music:  </b>Whistle while you work?  Music can be a break in itself—take a few minutes and listen to your favourite song, or something inspiring—or it can add a background that helps make something else you have to do more positive—something upbeat while folding the laundry, or getting through the bills.  If you’re a singer, of course, this could be a more active option:  sing to yourself, practice some lullabies—or if you play an instrument, play what makes you happy.  One study found that 30 minutes a day of listening to music helped to improve the mood of pregnant women.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_6"><b>Guided imagery:  </b>In guided imagery, you listen to a narration describing a relaxing scene, and imagine yourself in it—you can choose among several in the Imagery module—so you could transport yourself to walk along a beach, or in a favourite place, to take a fantasy break for a few minutes.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_7"><b>Body scan:  </b>n a body scan, you take a few minutes to listen to your body, mentally experiencing how you feel, physically, in the moment.  You can do this on your own, or use an audio guide module, “Body Scan”</string>
    <string name="stress_question_8"><b>Stretching: </b>Take 2-3 minutes and stretch whatever part of your body that feels like it needs it—feel your muscles as you raise your arms over your head, or move slowly and gently into an easy stretch.  Breathe.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_9"><b>Relaxation breathing: </b>Take a few minutes and pay attention to your breathing.  Notice how as you breathe in, slight tension builds, and then as you exhale, your body relaxes.  Slow down your breathing, so that you breathe in slowly, hold it, and exhale.  If you like a structure, you can do what is called “square breathing”:  inhale to a slow count of four, hold it to a count of four, exhale to a count of four, wait to a count of four, and then start over.    Do that a few times.  Breathe from your belly (as much as you can, being as it may be a bit full right now).  Feel your lungs expand.  Especially pay attention to how the tension drains out as you exhale.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_10"><b>Meditation:  </b>There are many traditions of meditation you may have tried or heard about.  Meditation practice can focus on a mantra (a special word), or mindfulness (paying attention to what is happening now), or breath, or a particular prayer.  If this interests you, read or learn more about a form of meditation that appeals to you.  Meditation can be done sitting, walking, standing, or even lying down. </string>
    <string name="stress_question_11"><b>Prayer:</b>Prayer may be a traditional set of words for your faith, or a personal conversation with the divine.  Many people find prayer helpful in times of stress and change. You may pray for help, for strength, for peace, for a particular outcome, or use words as a way to express gratitude, faith, worry, sadness—any thought or feeling.  Consider whether you would like to learn a particular prayer, or find a book of prayers to read, or just take some time for connection with your spirituality.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_12"><b>Massage: </b>Gentle massage can help with physical and emotional tension.  There are professional massage therapists who specialise in working with pregnant women.  You might also ask your partner for a massage—could be just your feet, or shoulders, or lower back, or whatever you are comfortable with.  One study taught partners of pregnant women to provide gentle massage, and found that not only did the women feel better, but the relationship improved. </string>
    <string name="stress_question_13"><b>Yoga: </b>Yoga is a slow, meditative form of exercise that has been used with pregnant women across cultures and settings; studies have shown that many women feel this improves their mental and physical wellbeing.  Often special yoga classes are available for pregnant women.  Other, similar forms of meditative exercise include Tai Chi and Qi Gong.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_14"><b>Gardening: </b>Getting out in the garden and helping things grow—or clearing away what shouldn’t be growing—might be what takes you out of your worries.  You can see what you’ve done.   Of course, be careful not to overdo it and strain something—but deadheading the roses might be just what the doctor ordered.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_15"><b>Laughter: </b>Laughter may actually be the best medicine—or at least a good one.  Read a funny book, watch a comedy, go out with some friends who make you laugh.  Make a plan now—what is likely to tickle your funny bone?</string>
    <string name="stress_question_16"><b>Reading: </b>Transport yourself with a story, or something that fascinates you.  For some people, reading is a trip away from the world, and that could be just what you need.  What is best for you—a book with short chapters, which you can read for 10 minutes?  Or a fantasy or thriller you can’t put down?</string>
    <string name="stress_question_17"><b>Make a list: </b>If something is worrying you—if you are afraid you won’t get it done, or there just seem to be too many things you’re juggling, and it all seems impossible—sometimes making a list can help.  Break it down into doable bits, and tick them off.  Maybe even make a schedule of when you can do each. </string>
    <string name="stress_question_18"><b>Call a friend: </b>For some people, it is really helpful to talk through their quandaries with someone who knows them—what is happening?  What shall I do?  Choose who you call thoughtfully—someone who is constructive, who will help you without ratcheting up the stress.  Sometimes, calling a friend might be for when you need NOT to talk about problems, but just to go out (or stay in) and do something you enjoy.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_19"><b>Take a bath:</b>For some, a bath can be a time just for you, to relax, to feel warmth and nice smells, maybe with some bubbles or oil…focus on the now, not on planning or worrying.  If you find your mind going back to the stresses, play with the bubbles.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_20"><b>Play: </b>What do you do that is playful?  Sometimes being with someone…a child, or a pet…who is completely absorbed in what you are doing—playing with a ball, or a toy, or blowing bubbles—can be a break from stress.  You could also play a game—in the real world, or on your phone or tablet.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_21"><b>Go outside: </b>For many people, being outside, especially in a natural setting, can lift your mood.  Especially in winter, getting a bit of sun and air can also do wonders for your wellbeing, even if the weather is not the best.</string>
    <string name="stress_question_22"><b>Feed yourself: </b>You (and your baby) need food to live and grow.  Remember to nurture  yourself with healthy, satisfying snacks.  What appeals to you to eat that will give you a moment of satisfaction and soothing, without guilt or worry?</string>
    <string name="stress_question_23"><b>Create something [art, or craft, or food?]: </b>Making something can provide distraction, and the satisfaction of having a tangible product.  Could be sewing or knitting something for the baby, or baking, or drawing or painting or crafting—whatever is your thing.  You might even try something new—take a class, or look it up on the internet.  Trash to treasures?  </string>

    <!-- other -->
    <string name="title_activity_information">Information</string>
    <string name="title_activity_doing">Exercises &amp; Information</string>
    <string name="title_activity_self_assessment">Self Assessment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_breathing_rate">Breathing Rate</string>
    <string name="title_activity_breathing_instructions">Breathing Instructions</string>
    <string name="title_activity_breathing_measure">Breathing Measure</string>
    <string name="title_activity_breathing_learn">Breathing Learn</string>
    <string name="title_activity_heart_rate">Heart Rate</string>
    <string name="title_activity_skin_temperature">Skin Temperature</string>
    <string name="title_activity_music">Music</string>
    <string name="button_record">Record</string>
    <string name="plusSymbol">+</string>
    <string name="minusSymbol">-</string>
    <string name="intervalLabel">Interval</string>
    <string name="title_activity_other_functionality">OtherFunctionalityActivity</string>
    <string name="assessment_heading">Your Resources and Strengths</string>
    <string name="assessment_text">We all have different things going for us: areas in which we are strong, feel confident, and have the supports and skills we need.
        This quiz is to help you to assess, and remember, what those areas are for you.</string>
    <string name="assessment_text_rate">For each of the following areas, rate yourself on a scale of 1 to 5.</string>
    <string name="assessment_heading1">Stress Management</string>
    <string name="assessment_text1">Everyone has stress.  There are lots of healthy ways to manage stress, but not all of them will be right for you.  This is a menu of different options for coping with stress—some you will have tried, some not—some will work for you, some not.  For now, just go through and rate each option, to create your personalized menu of stress busters.</string>
    <string name="strategy_assessment_text_rate">Everyone has stress.  There are lots of healthy ways to manage stress, but not all of them will be right for you.  This is a menu of different options for coping with stress—some you will have tried, some not—some will work for you, some not.  For now, just go through and rate each option, to create your personalized menu of stress busters.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_strength_reminders">Strength Reminders</string>

</resources>